### Coordonnées

www.linkedin.com/in/aurelie-bonal-452041191 (LinkedIn)

### Principales compétences

Diplomacy
International Relations
Strategic Communications

### Languages

Arabic (Elementary)

German (Elementary)

Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

English (Native or Bilingual)

French (Native or Bilingual)

Portuguese (Professional Working)

#### Certifications

1st dan/black belt

# **Aurelie Bonal**

Deputy Chief of Mission at Embassy of France in the United States Washington, District de Columbia, États-Unis

### Résumé

Currently deputy Ambassador at the French Embassy in DC. A seasoned French diplomat, I am a former student of the prestigious and now extinct ENA (National school for administration).

Previously Spokesperson at the French Embassy in London, I've spent almost 20 years advising French public stakeholders on their communication and their political strategy, mostly on European matters.

I managed intercultural teams in 4 countries and have learned 5 foreign languages.

Mother of 2, slow runner but fast learner, cat-lover, Aïkidoka for 24 years.

@AurelieBonal

# Expérience

Embassy of France in the United States Deputy Chief of Mission août 2020 - Present (3 ans 5 mois)

Washington DC-Baltimore Area

Ambassade de France au Royaume-Uni Press Counsellor and Embassy Spokesperson septembre 2016 - août 2020 (4 ans)

- Responsible for recommending lines to take on Franco-British matters for French ministers, Elysée and Ambassador
- In charge of Embassy's footprint in UK media and Embassy's social media. Covered crisis communication (terrorist attacks in the UK, French victims, Salisbury, etc)
- Personal contacts with most of the senior UK political journalists

Ministère de l'Europe et des Affaires étrangères Head for the Western and Nordic Europe Department septembre 2013 - août 2016 (3 ans)

Région de Paris, France

- Coordinated several bilateral summits between French President and British Prime Minister and participated in outlining conclusions and deliverables.
- Organised political and logistical aspects of HM the Queens's state visit in France in 2014 (as well as King of Sweden in 2014 and King of the Netherlands in 2016)
- Followed EU matters relating to the 10 countries under my remit (notably Euro-crisis, counter-terrorism, migration, the Brexit referendum)
- Covered COP21 French agenda in Nordic countries
- Produced political analysis and briefings for French Ministries & other public stakeholders

10 Countries under my remit: United-Kingdom, Netherlands, Belgium, Luxembourg, Norway, Sweden, Denmark, Ireland, Finland and Iceland

Channel Tunnel Intergovernmental Commission Government Representative septembre 2013 - août 2016 (3 ans)

Paris Area, France

I represented the French Ministry for Foreign Affairs at the Channel Tunnel Intergovernmental Commission. I participated in decisions and audits regarding:

- Safety issues in the tunnel and changes on safety requirements
- · Authorisation to place rail vehicles into service
- Economic regulation of the access to the Channel Tunnel network
- Getlink/Eurotunnel's management of the network
- Legal action between Eurostar and Eurotunnel

Ambassade de France en Irlande Deputy Head Of Mission décembre 2009 - août 2013 (3 ans 9 mois)

County Dublin, Ireland

- Covered the Irish financial crisis and produced briefings for the French government
- Sold and acquired new Embassy building in Dublin
- Interacted with most of the current Irish leading political figures
- Managed the Embassy team

Ambassade de France en Argentine Political Counsellor août 2005 - décembre 2009 (4 ans 5 mois)

Greater Buenos Aires, Argentina

- established personal exchanges with all current Argentinian political leaders and parties
- produced analysis on domestic situation in Argentina
- covered various national elections

# Ministère de l'Europe et des Affaires étrangères Desk Officer

avril 2002 - août 2007 (5 ans 5 mois)

Région de Paris, France

- produced analysis on situation of Armenia, Georgia and Azerbaidjan
- member of the OSCE negociating team on Nagorny Karabagh and UN team in Georgia
- electoral observer in Armenia and Georgia (OSCE)
- member of a fact-finding mission in Armenian-controlled territories surrounding Nagorno-Karabakh

#### **OSCE**

Mediator

avril 2002 - août 2007 (5 ans 5 mois)

Member of the French delegation of the Minsk group, dealing with the Nagorny-karabagh conflict

#### Ambassade de France en Syrie

Intern

août 2000 - janvier 2001 (6 mois)

Damascus, Syria

- Followed EU affairs during French presidency of the EU Council
- Followed press matters
- updated evacuation plan for the French community

## **Formation**

ENA - Ecole Nationale d'Administration

 $\cdot$  (2000 - 2002)

Sciences Po Aix

 $\cdot$  (1994 - 1998)